Brandon T. McBride

E-MAIL MCBRIDEBR@GMAIL.COM

SUMMARY

Information technology leader with 13 years of experience in DevOps, system administration, configuration management, quality assurance, QA automation, and continuous integration using agile methodologies. Experience working with PowerShell, Windows CLI, and Linux CLI. Deep knowledge base in network security and a high degree of aptitude in emerging technologies.

SKILLS

Server Administration	Cloud Solutions	Continuous Integration	PowerShell
Windows Server	Configuration Management	Containerization	DevOps
Linux	Network Security	Jenkins	Automation

WORK EXPERIENCE

CGI Technologies and Solutions

Lebanon, VA

March 2011 – Present

Senior DevOps Engineer - Federal

- Leading a team responsible for supporting environments dedicated to development teams.
- Stand up and configure new instance of Jenkins with scalable automation to manage client team environments.
- Monitor and administer server configurations on Windows Server 2016 and Linux RedHat operating systems such as DNS, Firewalls, user accounts, and permissions.
- Created PowerShell scripts to assist with automation of password resets within IIS and automate the deployment of server resources.
- Managing existing environments using Cloudbees Jenkins, Kubernetes, and Helm.
- Implement and manage an automated password update process on servers across all production environments to minimize cost and meet contractual deadlines.
- Work with security to encrypt configuration data residing on servers and lock down environments in production to meet strict security guidelines.
- Design and maintain automated deployment solutions to support Continuous Integration across multiple environments from Test to Production using Bitbucket, JIRA, Bamboo, and Octopus Deploy that fit within the Agile Scrum/SAFe Metholodigies.
- Work directly with development teams and the business to ensure proper code deployment and requirements are correct while managing the code base across all clients.

Test Manager – US Enterprise Markets

- Manage team of testers and coordinate with the business to plan UAT and Production Testing cycles for telecommunications software.
- Work with testing team to execute test plans for commercial software.
- Produce reporting metrics and results for presentation to the client.
- Report defects found during testing and manage them to resolution.

Scientific Research Corporation

Charleston, SC

June 2010 – March 2011

Technical Quality Analyst II

- Continuous set of up network test beds using Dell Servers, Cisco Routers, and work stations supporting the United States Navy's ship to shore communications.
- Continuous configuration and maintenance of network test bed using Red Hat Enterprise Linux and Windows based environments.
- Tested and approved network software during the System Test phase before moving it along to Production.
- Work directly with developers to get working Windows and Linux software delivered to the U.S. Navy within the Atlantic and Pacific fleets.
- Worked with government sponsors, developers, network engineers and technical writers.

CGI Technologies and Solutions

Lebanon, VA

January 2008 – June 2010

Test Analyst

- Extensive use of Mercury Quality Center as a defect tracking tool.
- Tested windows and web-based applications in a team environment.
- Worked with Process Engineers, Systems Engineers, and Test Managers in efforts to complete projects and testing in a timely manner.
- Created and maintained test plans, design steps and test scenario matrices.

EDUCATION

Appalachian State University

Boone, NC

- Bachelor of Science in Business Administration
- Major: Computer Information Systems